Rushi Samirbhai Patel

📱 : Halifax, NS 🕻 :+1 902809-0051 🗹 : rushi.patel@dal.ca in: www.linkedin.com/in/rushipatel95/ 🛈 : github.com/Rushipatel0995

SUMMARY

Developer and Mentor at the Google Developer Student Club at Dalhousie University. Dedicated speaker skilled in influencing students through effective teaching sessions of topics related to my almost 4 years of work experience in IT industry.

SKILLS

Java, C#, Selenium/WebDriver, Junit, Nunit, Spring MVC, Springboot, JPA Hibernate, MySQL, Gherkins, BDD SpecFlow, Jenkins, DuckCreek, Azure Devops, AWS, Git, Jira, Docker, SonarQube, Postman, and Apache Maven.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant – Software Engineering

April 2022 - Present

Faculty of Computer Science, DalOhousie University

- Involved in the development of new material for department courses by contributing to the creation of appropriate teaching materials to ensure that content and delivery methods satisfy learning objectives.
- Conducted labs for Test-driven development, Solid Principle, Design Patterns, and Gitflow workflow.
- Provided timely and frequent feedback to students, fostering an environment of open communication and interest in discovery.

QA Engineer

September 2020 - July 2021

Ness Technologies, Mumbai, India

- Configuring SonarQube and SauceLabs for executing scripts in parallel and cross browser testing and utilising SonarQube for automated static code analysis.
- As the only Automation Test Engineer in the project, developed a standalone project in Java to compare and list files (with details of all the files) from different AmazonS3 servers using AWS integrated with Apache Maven dependencies.

Associate Consultant

June 2020 - September 2020

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd., India

- Designed and implemented the automation framework of Chubb small commercial market place application by using Selenium/WebDriver, Nunit.
- Used Data Driven Framework to check the behavior of application with different inputs as parameters using Selenium.

Sr. Software Engineer

October 2017 - June 2020

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd., India

- Deploying the code in test as well in production environments with an added responsibility to merge the code using Tortoise SVN/Bitbucket.
- Responsible for creating the controllers and services to get the response using Spring MVC Framework and Hibernate.

EDUCATION

Master of Applied Computer Science

September 2021 – May 2023

Faculty of Computer Science, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Canada

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

July 2013 - June 2017

Gujarat Technological University, Gujarat, India

CGPA-8.09

CERTIFICATIONS

Basic Online First Aid Course Certified 2021 Customer Delight Award - Capgemini 2019 Advanced Online First Aid Course Certified 2021 Rising Star Award – Capgemini 2019 Online CPR Course Certified 2021 Star of the month – Capgemini 2020 Oracle Certified Associate Java Professional 2018 University Champion – Table Tennis 2013-2015 **ITIL Foundation** 2018 State Champion – Table Tennis 2014-2015 College Champion – Soccer 2014-2017

ACHIEVEMENTS

PROJECTS | MORE PROJECTS ON GITHUB

IglooDoor - Complete Password Security

- Led an agile team to plan, design, develop and deploy a responsive cloud-based web application that handles complete password management and ensuring the safest password by increasing the average password security by 65%.
- Used AWS services (Cloud Formation, Cognito, EC2, S3, VPC, Lambda, RDS, API Gateway) and integrated these services to run the application on AWS infrastructure.